Register of the Charles F. Darlington papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Charles F. Darlington papers
1924-1985
86032
Hoover Institution Archives
11 manuscript boxes (4.6 linear feet)
Memoirs, speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, printed matter, and photographs relating to American-Gabonese relations, the organizing conference of the United Nations, American foreign trade policy, international currency exchange activities of the League of Nations, the oil industry in the Middle East, and Democratic Party politics, especially during the 1956 and 1960 presidential elections.
Darlington, Charles F. (Charles Francis), 1904-1986.
Access
Collection is open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives in 1986.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
Charles Francis Darlington was an American businessman, diplomat, and economist who held several notable positions throughout his career. After graduating from Harvard in 1926, he served as a gold expert and currency specialist in the economic and financial section of the League of Nations from 1928 to 1931, followed by a position as financial advisor with the Bank for International Settlements in Basel.
In 1935, Darlington returned to the U.S. and became assistant chief of the Division of Trade Agreements under Secretary of State Cordell Hull. He also served as a lieutenant commander in the Navy during the Second World War. From May to June,1945, Darlington was secretary of the Steering, Executive, and Coordination Committee of the San Francisco Conference of the United Nations, where he helped draft the organization's charter. He stands as one of only a handful of Americans to be involved with both the United Nations and the League of Nations. In 1945, Darlington left his job with the government for a brief post with the General Motors Corporation, followed by a position with the Socony Vacuum (now Exxon Mobil) Oil Corporation, the latter of which involved negotiating contracts for the oil industry in the Middle East.
By 1956, Darlington had reduced his time working overseas with Mobil to become involved with the Westchester County Democratic Committee. Darlington's political involvement through Westchester included an unsuccessful bid for Bedford County Supervisor in 1956, as well as positions on numerous election committees in New York for both Adlai Stevenson and John F. Kennedy in the 1956 and 1960 presidential elections, respectively. Darlington was also a published author and wrote a number of articles for the New York Times in addition to drafts of speeches for both Stevenson and Kennedy.
In 1961, President Kennedy appointed Darlington U.S. Ambassador to Gabon, where he served until his retirement from the State Department in 1965. Darlington's experiences in Gabon, as well as his account of the 1964 coup d'etat against President Leon Mba, were published in a book co-authored with his wife, Alice, African Betrayal (1968).
Scope and Content of Collection
The Charles F. Darlington papers contain photographs, speeches and writings, correspondence, memoranda, and printed matter relating to American-Gabonese relations, the organizing conference of the United Nations, American foreign trade policy, international currency exchange activities of the League of Nations, the oil industry in the Middle East, and Democratic Party politics, especially the 1956 and 1960 presidential elections. Notable persons featured in the correspondence include: Eleanor Roosevelt, Adlai E. Stevenson, Walter Lippmann, Dean Acheson, John F. Kennedy, Albert Schweitzer, and Leon Mba. The collection is notable not only for its scope and content, but also for the existing organizational structure provided by Darlington. All series, organizational hierarchies, and folders maintain their original order and titles when possible. Handwritten notes by Darlington found in various folders also detail the scope of the material and his assessment of its historical value.
Democratic Party (U.S.); League of Nations.; United States. Dept. of State.; Currency question.; Diplomats--United States.; Gabon--Foreign relations--United States.; Petroleum industry and trade--Middle East.; Presidents--United States--Election--1956; Presidents--United States--Election--1960.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Foreign relations--Gabon.
- Biographical File, 1924-1968 (Box-folder 1: 1-6)
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains yearbooks, event agendas featuring Darlington as speaker, certificates, ambassador placard, newspaper articles about Darlington, agenda book from 1963, and other materials.
- Correspondence, 1926-1977, undated
  - General, 1931 October 22 - 1977 April 4, undated (Box-folder 1: 7)
    Includes general correspondence between Darlington and friends and colleagues. Also includes an undated group of letters identified by Darlington as "French letter and other communications, drafts of letters we wrote in Geneva, and memo of a press conference on trade agreements" in English, French, and German.
  - Commercial policy, 1956 June 22 - September 19 (Box-folder 1: 8)
    Includes correspondence regarding a memo sent by Darlington not included in the collection.
  - Job appointments, 1931 September 7 - 1966 October 19 (Box-folder 1: 9)
    Includes correspondence reflecting Darlington's contract negotiations, official job appointments, and official job resignations/retirement with the League of Nations, Bank for International Settlements, and U.S. Department of State.
  - Job hunt, 1933 November 28 - 1939 January 5 (Box-folder 1: 10-11)
    Includes letters about Darlington's attempts to obtain employment at the Federal Bank of New York, Office of Special Advisor to the President on Foreign Trade, U.S. Department of State, U.S. Steel Corporation, and General Motors Corporation. Also includes correspondence with U.S. Secretary of State Cordell Hull. Some letters are with their original envelopes and contain content notes/descriptions by Darlington, along with news clippings about the intended correspondent.
  - Letters of introduction, 1926 July 15 - 1930 May 26 (Box-folder 1: 12)
    Contains letters of introduction written for Darlington by colleagues, teachers, advisors, and community members in support of Darlington's attempts to gain employment with the League of Nations and Bank for International Settlements.
  - "Political General-Personal,", 1958 January 10 - 1959 August 14 (Box-folder 2: 1)
    Includes correspondence from Darlington's time as a member of the Bedford Democratic Committee in Bedford, New York.
  - "Transportation,", 1958 March 11 - 1960 August 30 (Box-folder 2: 2)
    Includes correspondence relating to Darlington's time as head of the transportation section of the Research Advisory Council of the Westchester County Democratic Commission. Retains original order with various reports and drafts written by Darlington included with the correspondence.
  - "War Period,", 1943 April 21 - 1949 August 15 (Box-folder 2: 3)
    Includes correspondence from Darlington's time serving in the Navy as a lieutenant commander. Also includes letters from Adlai Stevenson, Frank Knox, and Walter Lippmann.
- Speeches and Writings, 1934-1976, undated
  Contains speeches and writings by Darlington not already filed in a separate subject series. Several files include notes, articles, research materials, and drafts, as well as correspondence about the publication or speech. All files retain their original order and title when possible. Notable persons featured in the correspondence include Walter Lippmann, Eleanor Roosevelt, and Adlai Stevenson.
  - "Address Given at Binghamton New York,", 1956 March 23 (Box-folder 2: 4)
  - African Betrayal, 1966-1976, undated
    Includes correspondence, notes, drafts, edits, and other materials relating to African Betrayal, written by Darlington and his wife, Alice, about their time in Gabon and published in 1968. Maintains original order and uses Darlington's original folder titles.
    - "Chapters by Alice Darlington,", undated (Box-folder 2: 5)
    - "Comments on the book,", 1967-1976, undated (Box-folder 2: 6-7)
    - "Old pages that had to be retyped after bouts with the attorneys and the State Department,", undated (Box-folder 2: 8)
    - "Records of work with attorneys and the State Department,", 1967, undated (Box-folder 2: 9)
    - "General correspondence about preparation and sale of manuscript,", 1966-1967, undated (Box-folder 2: 10)
    - "Texts not used,", undated (Box-folder 2: 11)
  - "America 1970," speech written for John F. Kennedy during the 1960 presidential campaign, 1960 October-November (Box-folder 3: 1)
  - "An Inquiry Into What Should Be the Attitude of the Republican Party Toward the Trade Agreements Policy,", 1939 May 19 (Box-folder 3: 2)
  - "Attitude Towards Communist World," unpublished article written for the New York Times, 1960 September-October (Box-folder 3: 3)
  - "Book Club Luncheon" (speech), 1968 April 25 (Box-folder 3: 4)
  - "Ends of the Earth Dinner" (speech), 1968 December 6 (Box-folder 3: 5)
  - "Financial Sales: The Bank for International Settlements," in News and Views, p. 17, 1939 November (Box-folder 3: 6)
  - "Foreign Economic Policy: A Program for Democratic Action,", 1956 July 18 (Box-folder 3: 7)
  - "Letter to the Editor," New York Times, 1960 May 30 (Box-folder 3: 8)
  - "Lion's Club Speech,", 1966 November 22 (Box-folder 3: 9)
  - Memoirs, 1975 November - 1976 March
    - Part I, 1975 November (Box-folder 3: 10)
    - Part II, 1976 March (Box-folder 3: 11-12)
  - "Memorandum on Our Foreign Commercial Policy,", 1940 September (Box-folder 3: 13)
  - "Milwaukee, September 10th," speech written for governor Adlai E. Stevenson in support of John F. Kennedy during the 1960 presidential election, 1960 June-August (Box-folder 3: 14)
  - "Not the Goal, Only the Means," New York Times, 1960 July 3 (Box-folder 3: 15-16)
  - Notes, 1964 December 9 (Box-folder 4: 1)
  - "Notes for Mr. Wilkie on Foreign Affairs and Foreign Trade,", 1940 July 22 (Box-folder 4: 2)
  - "Notes on a Lecture for Columbia,", undated (Box-folder 4: 3)
  - Public addresses, 1965 November 27 - 1968 February 19 (Box-folder 4: 4)
    Contains correspondence relating to public addresses given by Darlington and not included in the collection, or invitations to give public addresses rejected by Darlington. Folders retain original titles.
  - "Some Reflections on the Central Problem of Our Times,", undated (Box-folder 4: 5)
  - "Speech at Lynchburg, Virginia,", 1964 November (Box-folder 4: 6)
  - "Suggested Theme for Speech on the Underdeveloped Countries,", undated (Box-folder 4: 7)
    Contains note: "Written for President Johnson at request of Parker [?] Goldman in the White House."
  - "Talk at the Ashbury Methodist Church,", 1969 January 14 (Box-folder 4: 8)
  - "Talk Before the Westchester County Historical Society,", 1968 February 18 (Box-folder 4: 9)
  - "Talk Given at the Bedford Farmers' Club,", 1967 April 26 (Box-folder 4: 10)
  - "The Conduct of Foreign Trade," Proceedings of the Academy of Political Science, Volume 14, p.36, 1940 May (Box-folder 4: 11)
  - "The Department of State's Relation to Our Foreign Markets and European Aid Programs, Remarks Made at Paris Conference,", 1948 May 19 (Box-folder 4: 12)
  - "The Development of the System of Exchange Clearing,", circa 1933 (Box-folder 4: 13)
  - "The Huguenot Society, Speech Given at the Huguenot Society of America Annual Luncheon,", 1968 December 7 (Box-folder 4: 14)
  - "The Importance of African Students, Address at the Fox Lane School,", 1968 February 28 (Box-folder 4: 15)
  - "The Quality of Independence, Address Given at the Spring Conference of the Westchester County Federation of Women's Clubs,", 1968 April 26 (Box-folder 4: 16)
  - "The Toast to the Art of Rowing, Remarks Given at the 20th Annual Oxford and Cambridge Boat Race Dinner,", 1966 March 22 (Box-folder 4: 17)
  - "The United Kingdom and Canadian Agreements and the Trade Agreements Program,", undated (Box-folder 4: 18)
  - "The United Nations, Address Given at Mount Kisco,", 1946 March 25 (Box-folder 4: 19)
  - "The War and Our Foreign Trade, Address Given Before the Meeting of the Packaging Agents Association of Syracuse,", 1940 June (Box-folder 4: 20)
  - "Trouble in the Parkways," unpublished draft, 1961 July-September (Box-folder 4: 21)
  - "United States Commercial Policy as Affected by the War," address given at the Institute of World Affairs of the Students International Union, 1940 July (Box-folder 4: 22)
  - "United States Foreign Trade: Hands Across the Sea Plane," in American Bankers Association Journal, 1934 April, p. 28 (Box-folder 4: 23)
  - "Why the World Looks to the U.N.," article published under name of Adlai E. Stevenson, written by both Stevenson and Darlington, New York Times, 1960 September-October (Box-folder 4: 24)
    File maintains original order with correspondence and edited drafts from both men. Also includes newspaper clippings collected by Darlington of other articles addressing the same subject.
  - "Work and Functions of the Financial Committee (League of Nations),", 1930 (Box-folder 4: 25)
- League of Nations File, 1930-1933, undated
  Contains correspondence from Darlington's time as an advisor in the Economic and Financial Section of the League of Nations, portraits and group photographs of League members (all labeled and identified), and two publications from the Economic and Financial Section of the League titled "Work and Functions of the Financial Committee" and "Monetary and Economic Conference: Draft Annotated Agenda." Correspondence maintains original identification system.
  - Correspondence, 1930-1931, undated
    - Aftalion, Professor Henri, 1930 July 25 (Box-folder 4: 26)
    - Agricultural credits, 1931 February 16 (Box-folder 4: 27)
    - Albania, 1930 June 2 (Box-folder 4: 28)
    - Alberti, Mario, Dr., 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 29)
    - de Albornoz, Don Severo Carillo, 1930 August 18 (Box-folder 4: 30)
    - Algeria, 1930 August 1 (Box-folder 4: 31)
    - Allen, Frederick H., 1931 January 14 (Box-folder 4: 32)
    - Argentina, 1930 August 8-October 8 (Box-folder 4: 33)
    - Australia, 1930 June 26 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 4: 34)
    - Austria, 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 4: 35)
    - Bachi, Professeur Riccardo, 1931 March 20-August 10 (Box-folder 4: 36)
    - Bachmann, G., 1930 June 26-July 18 (Box-folder 4: 37)
    - Balogh, T., 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 4: 38)
    - Barbosa-Carneiro, 1931 May 27 (Box-folder 4: 39)
    - Basch, Ant., Dr., 1930 June 27 - 1931 September 8 (Box-folder 4: 40)
    - Belgian Congo, 1930 July 11-18 (Box-folder 4: 41)
    - Belgium, 1930 June 26-September 9 (Box-folder 4: 42)
    - Bolivia, 1930 June 26-August 28 (Box-folder 4: 43)
    - Bonn, Professor M. J., 1930 August 6 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 4: 44)
    - Borberg, William, 1930 August 18 (Box-folder 4: 45)
    - de Bordes, Dr. J. van Walre, 1930 July 30 (Box-folder 4: 46)
    - von Bortkiewicz, Professor Ladislaus, 1931 February 13-May 27 (Box-folder 4: 47)
    - Son Excellence M. Bouroff, 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 4: 48)
    - Brazil, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 49)
    - Bruins, G. W., Dr., 1931 January 14 (Box-folder 4: 50)
    - Bulgaria, 1930 April 25 - June 26 (Box-folder 4: 51)
    - Butler, 1930 July 11 (Box-folder 4: 52)
    - Buxton, Major, 1931 April 27 (Box-folder 4: 53)
    - Canada, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 54)
    - Carroll, Marie J., 1930 June 3 - 1931 July 10 (Box-folder 4: 55)
    - Cassel, Professor Gustav, 1931 July 8-September 8 (Box-folder 4: 56)
    - de Chalendar, M. le Comte, 1930 July 20 - 1931 August 6 (Box-folder 4: 57)
    - Charron, Rene, 1930 November 15 - 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 4: 58)
    - Chicago Press, 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 4: 59)
    - Chile, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 60)
    - Chilton, Carroll Brent, 1930 September 13 (Box-folder 4: 61)
    - China, 1930 August 28 (Box-folder 4: 62)
    - Clavier, 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 4: 63)
    - Clements, Jesse, 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 4: 64)
    - Coats, R. H., 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 4: 65)
    - Colombia, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 4: 66)
    - Commission Mixte d'emigration Greco-Bulgare, 1930, undated (Box-folder 4: 67)
    - Costa Rica, 1930 August 28 - 1931 March 11 (Box-folder 4: 68)
    - L'Association Cotonniere de Belgique, 1930 September 8 (Box-folder 4: 69)
    - Cuba, 1930 June 26 - 1931 April 8 (Box-folder 4: 70)
    - Danzig, 1930 September 13 (Box-folder 4: 71)
    - Davis, Norman, 1931 September 8 (Box-folder 4: 72)
    - Delaquis, Professeur Ernest, 1931 March 20-April 8 (Box-folder 4: 73)
    - Denmark, 1930 June 26 - 1931 April 8 (Box-folder 4: 74)
    - Distribution, 1930 June 26 - 1931 February 21 (Box-folder 5: 1)
    - Dorning, Dr. H., 1931 June 18 (Box-folder 5: 2)
    - East Africa, 1930 June 26-July 18 (Box-folder 5: 3)
    - Eddy, Charles E., 1930 February 15 (Box-folder 5: 4)
    - Egypt, 1930 June 26-August 28 (Box-folder 5: 5)
    - Eisler, Robert, Dr., 1930 November 12 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 6)
    - Estonia, 1931 June 18-July 21 (Box-folder 5: 7)
    - Eulambio, 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 5: 8)
    - Eyskens, Gaston, 1931 September 8 (Box-folder 5: 9)
    - Felkin, A. E., 1931 September 28 (Box-folder 5: 10)
    - Fermor, L. L., 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 5: 11)
    - Financial Committee, 1931 August 10 (Box-folder 5: 12)
    - Finland, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 13)
    - Finlayson, H. C. F., 1931 February 13-July 21 (Box-folder 5: 14)
    - Fisher, J. Lenox, 1930 July 11-July 25 (Box-folder 5: 15)
    - France, 1930 June 27 (Box-folder 5: 16)
    - Freiberger, et. al, undated (Box-folder 5: 17)
    - Gebhard, Professor H., 1931 February 13-18 (Box-folder 5: 18)
    - Germany, 1930 August 18 (Box-folder 5: 19)
    - Gilbert, Prentiss, 1930 December 19 (Box-folder 5: 20)
    - Gold Delegation, 1931 May 29 (Box-folder 5: 21)
    - Grafftey Smith, A. P., 1931 February 18 (Box-folder 5: 22)
    - Graham, 1930 July 9-December 29 (Box-folder 5: 23)
    - Greece, 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 24)
    - Gregory (Professor), 1930 July 26-July 30 (Box-folder 5: 25)
    - Guatemala, 1930 August 28 (Box-folder 5: 26)
    - Haberler, Dr. Gottfried, 1931 April 13-August 15 (Box-folder 5: 27)
    - Hentsch, O. E., 1931 April 8 (Box-folder 5: 28)
    - Himmel, 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 5: 29)
    - Holloway, Dr., 1930 November 17 (Box-folder 5: 30)
    - Hudson, Holland, 1930 November 17 (Box-folder 5: 31)
    - Hungary, 1930 June 2-August 16 (Box-folder 5: 32)
    - Iceland, 1930 June 6-July 11 (Box-folder 5: 33)
    - India, 1930 June 26-November 25 (Box-folder 5: 34)
    - Indo-China, 1930 June 27-July 18 (Box-folder 5: 35)
    - International Chamber of Commerce, 1930 June 10 (Box-folder 5: 36)
    - International Club, 1930 November 6-18 (Box-folder 5: 37)
    - Irish Free State, 1930 June 26 - 1931 April 16 (Box-folder 5: 38)
    - Italy, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 39)
    - Jacklin, 1930 July 17-August 11 (Box-folder 5: 40)
    - Janssen, Albert, 1930 August 23 - 1931 August 15 (Box-folder 5: 41)
    - Japan, 1930 June 2 (Box-folder 5: 42)
    - Jay, N. Dean, 1930 September 25 (Box-folder 5: 43)
    - de Jenner, 1931 June 6 (Box-folder 5: 44)
    - Kemmerer, Professor E. W., 1930 June 27-November 15 (Box-folder 5: 45)
    - Kempner, Dr. Paul, 1931 July 9-August 15, undated (Box-folder 5: 46)
    - Kershagl, Dr. Richard, 1930 June 27-July 25 (Box-folder 5: 47)
    - van Kleffens, 1930 July 18 (Box-folder 5: 48)
    - Latvia, 1930 June 26-July 5 (Box-folder 5: 49)
    - Son Excellence M. Liaptcheff, 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 5: 50)
    - Lithuania, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 51)
    - Lockwood, Edgar, 1931 February 18 (Box-folder 5: 52)
    - Lopez, Pablo, 1930 August 18 (Box-folder 5: 53)
    - Loveday, undated (Box-folder 5: 54)
    - Son Excellence M. I. Lugosiann, 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 5: 55)
    - Lyon, Charles E., 1930 December 27 (Box-folder 5: 56)
    - Macdonald, 1931 February 20 (Box-folder 5: 57)
    - Madagascar, 1930 July 27-July 5 (Box-folder 5: 58)
    - Mant, Sir Reginald, 1930 July 25-1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 59)
    - Martin, Andre, 1931 September 12-18 (Box-folder 5: 60)
    - Martineque, et. al, 1930 June 27 (Box-folder 5: 61)
    - Mayrhofer, undated (Box-folder 5: 62)
    - McIver, D. T., 1931 September 18 (Box-folder 5: 63)
    - McLeod, Clarence J., 1930 November 15 (Box-folder 5: 64)
    - Meissner, Dr., 1930 June 27 (Box-folder 5: 65)
    - Melchior, Dr. Carl, 1930 July 25-August 23 (Box-folder 5: 66)
    - ter Meulen, C. E., et. al, 1930 July 30 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 67)
    - Mexico, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 68)
    - Son Excellence M. de Michelis, 1931 February 13 (Box-folder 5: 69)
    - Mills, Frederic, 1930 September 3 (Box-folder 5: 70)
    - Mint (Royal), 1930 June 2-November 15 (Box-folder 5: 71)
      Relates to Royal Mints of South Africa, Australia, and London.
    - Mireaux, 1931 March 20-July 1 (Box-folder 5: 72)
    - Mlynarski, Dr. Feliks, 1930 July 11 - 1931 August 15 (Box-folder 5: 73)
    - Monacco, 1930 August 16 (Box-folder 5: 74)
    - Montesino, Carlos G., 1930 December 19 (Box-folder 5: 75)
    - Morocco, 1930 June 27 (Box-folder 5: 76)
    - Myers, Denys P., 1930 June 3 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 77)
    - Nagler, Dr. L., 1931 May 26 (Box-folder 5: 78)
    - Netherlands, 1930 June 26-July 18 (Box-folder 5: 79)
    - New Zealand, 1930 June 26-July 21 (Box-folder 5: 80)
    - Neimeyer, Sir Otto, 1930 June 27-August 23 (Box-folder 5: 81)
    - di Nola, A., 1931 February 13-27 (Box-folder 5: 82)
    - Norway, 1930 June 26-July 16 (Box-folder 5: 83)
    - Palamas, L. C., 1930 June 27 - 1931 March 9 (Box-folder 5: 84)
    - Palestine, 1930 June 26 (Box-folder 5: 85)
    - Paraguay, 1930 August 28-September 13 (Box-folder 5: 86)
    - Pavlowsky, G., 1931 June 18 (Box-folder 5: 87)
    - Peaslee, Amos J., 1930 December 17 (Box-folder 5: 88)
    - Persia, 1930 June 27-September 18 (Box-folder 5: 89)
    - Peru, 1930 June 26-September 26 (Box-folder 5: 90)
    - Philippine Islands, 1930 August 28-September 8 (Box-folder 5: 91)
    - Pinsent, G. H. S., 1931 July 14 (Box-folder 5: 92)
    - Poland, 1930 September 13 (Box-folder 5: 93)
    - Police - Belgium, 1931 May 29 (Box-folder 5: 94)
    - Police - Vienna, 1931 May 26 (Box-folder 5: 95)
    - Poplawski, Auguste, 1931 February 13-March 20 (Box-folder 5: 96)
    - Popovics, 1930 June 27-July 18 (Box-folder 5: 97)
    - Pospisil, Dr. Vilem, 1930 August 23 - 1931 July 21 (Box-folder 5: 98)
    - Post, Arthur E., 1931 January 14-April 29 (Box-folder 5: 99)
    - Potts, Frederic A., 1931 July 14 (Box-folder 5: 100)
    - Publications Committee, 1931 May 8 (Box-folder 5: 101)
    - Quesnay, Pierre, 1931 January 19 (Box-folder 5: 102)
    - Rainer, Gildo, 1930 April 30-December 19 (Box-folder 5: 103)
    - Raphael, 1931 August 7 (Box-folder 5: 104)
    - Reed, Harold L., 1930 July 30 (Box-folder 5: 105)
    - Regard, E., 1931 July 1 (Box-folder 5: 106)
    - Reymond, 1931 February 18-21 (Box-folder 5: 107)
    - Riddleberger, 1930 November 28 (Box-folder 5: 108)